ibx.com 2001-04-08

# IBC: Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices of Independence Blue Cross in connection with www.ibx.com and all other Web sites owned and operated by Independence Blue Cross. Independence Blue Cross can be contacted by mail at 1901 Market Street, Philadelphia, PA 19103 -1480, attention Manager, Public Relations, by phone at 215-241-2400, or by e-mail at [webteam@ibx.com](mailto:webteam@ibx.com).

****

**1\. Collection of Personal Information from Site Visitors**

Independence Blue Cross may collect and/or track (1) the home server domain names, e-mail addresses, type of client computer, files downloaded, search engine used, operating system, and type of Web browser of visitors to Independence Blue Cross’ Web site, (2) the e-mail addresses of visitors that communicate with Independence Blue Cross via e-mail, (3) information knowingly provided by the visitor in online forms, registration forms, surveys, e-mail, contest entries, and other online avenues (including demographic and personal profile data), and (4) aggregate and user-specific information on which pages visitors access.

Independence Blue Cross may place Internet "cookies" on visitors’ hard drives. Internet cookies save data about individual visitors, such as the visitor’s name, password, user-name, shopping cart, screen preferences, and the pages of a site viewed by the visitor. When the visitor revisits Independence Blue Cross’ Web site, Independence Blue Cross may recognize the visitor by the Internet cookie and customize the visitor’s experience accordingly. Visitors may decline Internet cookies, if any, by using the appropriate feature of their Web client software, if available.

When a visitor performs a search within Independence Blue Cross’ Web site, Independence Blue Cross may record information identifying the visitor or linking the visitor to the search performed. Independence Blue Cross may also record limited information for every search request and uses that information only to solve technical problems with the service and to calculate overall usage statistics.

****

**2\. Use of Personal Data Collected**

Personal data collected by Independence Blue Cross may be used by Independence Blue Cross for many reasons, for example, for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, for a statistical analysis of users’ behavior, for product development, for content improvement, or to customize the content and layout of Independence Blue Cross’ site. Aggregate data on visitors’ home servers may be used for internal purposes or provided to third parties such as marketing firms. Individually identifying information, such as names, postal and e-mail addresses, phone numbers, and other personal information which visitors voluntarily provide to Independence Blue Cross may be (i) added to Independence Blue Cross’ databases and used for future calls and mailings regarding site updates, new products and services, and upcoming events, or (ii) provided to reputable third parties who provide products and services which Independence Blue Cross believes that visitors may be interested in purchasing or obtaining.

****

**3\. Disclosure of Personal Data to Third Parties**

Any third party to which Independence Blue Cross shares, rents, sells, or otherwise discloses personal data for marketing purposes will be under a contractual obligation to use the personal data solely for marketing products and services which Independence Blue Cross determines, in its sole judgment, that visitors might find of interest. Independence Blue Cross will use its reasonable efforts to identify whether such third parties may have products or services of interest to visitors to Independence Blue Cross’ site. However, such parties are independent third parties over which Independence Blue Cross exercises no control, and therefore Independence Blue Cross is not responsible for their conduct, products, or services, and will not be liable therefor. Independence Blue Cross will only disclose to third parties information in aggregate form, that is publicly available, and/or that is knowingly and voluntarily disclosed by visitors.

****

**4\. Security Measures**

Independence Blue Cross has implemented numerous security features to prevent the unauthorized release of or access to personal information. For example, all Independence Blue Cross employees are required to certify their understanding that personal information is considered confidential, that it is important to safeguard personal information, and that Independence Blue Cross will take appropriate action against any employee who fails to acknowledge these facts or adhere to the requisite standards of conduct. Please be advised, however, that the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to/from Independence Blue Cross via this site or e-mail cannot be guaranteed. Accordingly, Independence Blue Cross is not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. For more private communication, visitors who have health coverage through or administered by Independence Blue Cross can contact Independence Blue Cross by telephone at the number listed on their member identification card. Any visitor can contact Independence Blue Cross by telephone at 215-241-2400.

****

**5\. Opt-Out Right**

Visitors may opt out of having their personally identifiable information retained by Independence Blue Cross, used by Independence Blue Cross for secondary purposes, disclosed to third parties, or used by Independence Blue Cross or third parties to send promotional correspondence to the visitor by contacting Independence Blue Cross via postal mail, e-mail, or telephone at the addresses above. (This does not apply to collection of the type of Web browser of visitors to Independence Blue Cross’ Web site.)

****

**6\. Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data**

Upon request via postal mail, e-mail, or phone, Independence Blue Cross will provide to visitors a summary of any personally identifiable information retained by Independence Blue Cross regarding the visitor. Visitors may modify, correct, change or update personally identifiable information that Independence Blue Cross has collected via this Web site or may cause their personal record to be removed from Independence Blue Cross’ database by contacting Independence Blue Cross via postal mail, e-mail, or telephone at the addresses above.

****

**7\. Collection of Personal Data from Children**

To the extent that Independence Blue Cross is able to determine the age of users by their submissions to or communications with Independence Blue Cross’ Web site, Independence Blue Cross will not knowingly (a) collect or post information from individuals under the age of sixteen ("children") without their parent’s or guardian’s consent, or (b) provide any personally identifying information collected from children, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatever.

If registration is required for any services on the Independence Blue Cross Site, and a user submits information to Independence Blue Cross’ Web site through such a registration process that indicates that such user is a child, the child’s parent or guardian will be alerted to the child’s registration and will be provided instructions on how the parent or guardian can delete the child’s registration, if so desired. No information collected through Independence Blue Cross’ Web site from users self-identified as children will knowingly be used for any direct marketing or promotional purposes. If there are no age restrictions on a contest which requires registration, and if a child wins, notification and prizes will be sent to the parent(s) or guardian(s) identified in the initial registration process.

****

**8\. Independence Blue Cross’ Right to Contact User**

Independence Blue Cross reserves the right to contact site visitors regarding account status and changes to the subscriber agreement, privacy statement, or any other policies or agreements relevant to site visitors.

**9\. Independence Blue Cross’ Right to Change Privacy Statement**

Independence Blue Cross reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time by notifying visitors of the existence and location of the new or revised privacy statement. Any change to this Privacy Statement shall be effective as to any visitor that has accepted the IBC Web Site Terms and Conditions before the change was made.

**Back to Home Page**
